Dramatics Files, 1878-1949
Smith College Archives
Dramatics Files
1878-1949
Smith College.
RG 80 UUID:3a72f91c-5a29-4eb1-8dfd-c28cf1b34ff0
19 boxes (8 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
Records consist of programs, photographs, press releases, articles, notes and prompt books relating to student productions at Smith between the years 1878 and 1949. These include all House Dramatics, Division of Dramatics, Alpha-Phi Kappa Psi, Theater Workshop, Dramatic Association and early Theater Department performances.
The first dramatic productions at Smith were performed by members of societies in the individual student houses on campus. The first of these was formed by Hatfield House in January of 1878 and was named Alpha Society. Washburn and Hubbard Houses soon followed with Olla Podrida in the fall of 1878 and Tertium Quid in 1879, respectively. Houses also occasionally banded together into groups under one name. Sarm Ganok was the name for the Stoddard- Dewey-Hatfield Houses group, and was adapted from the Chinese words for "Three Houses." To these was added Senior Dramatics in 1883 as a feature of Commencement week, although not officially added to the program until 1887. In 1889 the various dramatic societies had achieved official recognition by the administration of the College and in 1891 it became customary for performances to be held in town at the newly-opened Academy of Music. In 1896, owing to the tremendous popularity of Alpha Society, a sister organization was formed, called Phi Kappa Psi, and by 1901 most of the academic departments were also putting on shows. By 1908 the number of productions had out-paced itself to such an extent as to require limitations. The house dramatic groups were dissolved and in their place a divisional system based on class year was instituted. Four new groups were thus formed, each giving one show per year. The groups were called Cap and Bells, Sock and Buskin, The Players and The Mummers. This system was in turn discarded in 1919 when Samuel A. Eliot, of the Department of English Language and Literature, developed the Dramatics Association to replace it and added a course in play production to the Spoken English curriculum. In 1927 even the Senior Dramatics were taken over and all productions were given through the Dramatics Association and the Theatre Workshop, as the performances by Eliot's students were called. That same year also marked the first year of an actor/actress exchange with Amherst College and an end to the tradition of all-female casts in Smith plays. The Department of Theatre was not formed until the 1942-43 academic year, at which time Hallie Flannagan was made its chair. Seven years later, due to flagging student interest and lack of funds, the Dramatics Association voted to merge with the theatre department. All productions thereafter were produced by the department.
The Dramatics files consist of approximately 8 linear feet of programs, photographs, press releases, articles, notes and prompt books relating to the student productions at Smith between the years 1878 and 1949. These include all House Dramatics, Division of Dramatics, Alpha-Phi Kappa Psi, Theater Workshop, Dramatic Association and early Theater Department performances. For the early productions of the Theater Department, one should also consult the departmental production files, which are more complete. Senior Dramatics files are kept with the records of that class, departmental productions with the records of the department and faculty shows are filed with the faculty records. Brackets around any title, date, or organization indicate an uncertain attribution due to ambiguities in the content of the file. Dramatics files are arranged in chronological order.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
All files are open to research according to the regulations of the College Archives.
History of the Collection
No true provenance is known for the Dramatics records. Most likely they were transferred to the Archives from a number of possible sources including the Department of Theatre, the Dramatics Association and by alumnae donation.
Search Terms
Smith College.; College and school drama--Massachusetts--Northampton.; Theater--Massachusetts--Northampton.; Smith College.
Additional Information
Related Material
For the early productions of the Theater Department, one should also consult the departmental production files, which are more complete. Senior Dramatics files are kept with the records of that class, departmental productions with the records of the department and faculty shows are filed with the faculty records.
- General (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Dramatic Association - Correspondence 1931, 1947-48 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- History (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Council - Photographs (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Dramatics - list by house and dramatics association, etc (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Organization (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Unidentified photos (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Anniversaries (Box 1, Folder 8)
- List of plays, index (not complete) 1883-1960 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Dramatics no date (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Dramatics, informal and skits (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Olla Podrida
  - Oct. 2, 1880 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - A Smith Optimal (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - An Early Phase of Civilization (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Oct. 23, 1880 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Pygmalion (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Catacombs (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - A Surprise Party (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Nov. 17, 1880 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - A Pretty Piece of Business (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Jan. 22, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Magic Mirror (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Charades (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Merton's Laws of Motion (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - A Take-off on Yale Serenades (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Dutch Dolls (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Feb. 19, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Kafoozalum (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - A Scene in a Railway Car (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Tertium Quid
  - Feb. 23, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Pinafore of the Revolution (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - May 11, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - A Love of a bonnet (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Love Epic of the 18th Century (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - The Hunchback (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Olla Podrida
  - May 28, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Shooting Star (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Jun. 10, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Oedipus Tyrannus (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Tertium Quid
  - Nov. 2, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - A Syllogism (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - The Flower Greeting (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - scenes from Faust (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Development a la Chinois (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Olla Podrida
  - Feb. 11, 1882 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - An Apology (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Masonic Initiation (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Sketch showing effect of higher education on the feminine mind (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Place aux Dames (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Mrs. McWilliams in a Thunderstorm (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Tertium Quid
  - Mar. 8, 1882 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - The Lost Heir (a reading) (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - The Bashful Man (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Robby Shaftoe (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Boston Dip (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Apr. 26, 1882 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Apples (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Widow Larkin's Bonnet (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Olla Podrida
  - May 29, 1882 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Circle (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Tertium Quid
  - May 31, 1882 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Tableaux (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - My Uncle's Will (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Jun. 13, 1882 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Among My Books (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Mother Michel and her Cat (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Nov. 24, 1882 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - The Spirit of the Ninety-two, or the Coming Woman (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Jan. 31, 1883 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Matrimonial Advertisement (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Shadow Pantomimes (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - May 2, 1883 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Pictures (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - The Loves of a Lover (Box 2, Folder 20)
- [House Dramatics]
  - 1883-1884 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- [House Dramatics]
  - Jun. 4, 1884 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - The Cricket on the Hearth (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Tertium Quid
  - Jan. 28, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Lights Out (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - What Katy did at School (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Olla Podrida
  - Feb. 4, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Little Nell (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Peggoty (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Mrs. Macstinger (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - May 6, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - The Spanish Student (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - May 9, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Which is Which (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - May 7, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Sleeping Beauty (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Evangeline (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - The Beggar Maid (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - [1885-1886] (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - The Register (Box 2, Folder 28)
- [House Dramatics]
  - Oct. 7, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - The Baron's Gloves (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Pictures (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Olla Podrida
  - Nov. 18, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Oh! The Sparkling Genius of Washburn Hall (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Dewey House - photographs [1885-1886] (Box 2, Folder 31)
- [House Dramatics]
  - Oct. 21, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - The Honeymoon (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Tertium Quid
  - Feb. 10, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Engaged (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Olla Podrida (Box 2)
  - Feb. 3, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - The Garroters (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Mar. 11, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Duodecette (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Past and Present (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - A Train of Thought (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - May 19, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Cinderella (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Sweethearts (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Tertium Quid
  - Oct. 20, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - The Three Little Kittens and the Land of Pie (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Olla Podrida
  - Oct. 27, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Married for Money (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Jan. 21, 1887 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Oliver Twist (scene) (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Five Sisters of York tableau (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Nicholas Nickleby (scenes) (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Our Mutual Friend (scene) (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Feb. 2, 1887 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - The Decorative Sister (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - [1887-1888] (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - photographs (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Oct. 19, 1887 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Young Mr. Pritchard (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Tertium Quid
  - Oct. 26, 1887 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Atchi (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Dec. 7, 1887 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - The Sacred Flame of Torinji (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Mar. 7, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - The Rose and the Ring (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Olla Podrida
  - Mar. 14, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Lend Me Five Shillings (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Tertium Quid
  - May 16, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - A Husband to Order (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Olla Podrida
  - May 30, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - My Uncle's Will (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Place aux Dames (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Nov. 21, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - The Cool Collegians (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Tertium Quid
  - 1888 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - One Summer (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Feb. 27, 1889 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Esmerelda (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Olla Podrida
  - Mar. 13, 1889 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Our Mutual Friend (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Tertium Quid
  - May 29, 1889 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - The Sleeping Car (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Olla Podrida
  - Jun. 5, 1889 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - A Browning Courtship (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Tertium Quid
  - fall 1889 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Russian Honeymoon (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Olla Podrida
  - 1889-1890 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Jufrow van Steen (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Wallace House
  - Jan. 29, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Oh Madame (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Tertium Quid
  - Mar. 5, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Midsummer Night's Dream (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Olla Podrida
  - May 21, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - My Lord in Livery (Box 3, Folder 9)
- [House Dramatics]
  - Jun. 4, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - A Scrap of Paper (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Hatfield House
  - Jun. 7, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - A Box of Monkeys (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Tertium Quid
  - Oct. 31, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Change Partners (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Olla Podrida
  - Nov. 19, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Cricket on the Hearth (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Hatfield House
  - Nov. 29, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Turn Him Out (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Wallace House
  - Dec. 17, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Engaged (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Tertium Quid
  - 1890 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - The Vicar of Wakefield (Box 3, Folder 16)
- [81 Bridge Street]
  - [1890] (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - The Girl he Left Behind him (Box 3, Folder 17)
- [House Dramatics]
  - 1891-1892 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Kitchen Colonels (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Tertium Quid
  - Jan. 25, 1891 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - The Garroters (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Sarm Ganok
  - Feb. 18, 1891 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - She Stoops to Conquer (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Olla Podrida
  - May 6, 1891 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Heir at Law (Box 3, Folder 21)
- [House Dramatics]
  - May 16, 1891 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Who's to Win Him (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Olla Podrida
  - May 20, 1891 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - The Snowball (Box 4, Folder 1)
- [House Dramatics]
  - Jun. 11, 1891 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Willful Ward (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Sarm Ganok
  - Nov. 11, 1891 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - A Fair Barbarian (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Tertium Quid
  - Dec. 5, 1891 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - A Rice Pudding (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Wallace House
  - Jan. 27, 1892 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Portrait of a Lady (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Olla Podrida
  - Mar. 2, 1892 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - B.B. and P. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Tertium Quid
  - May 10-14, 1892 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Aunt Serena (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - May 15, 1892 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Sweethearts (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Sarm Ganok
  - May 18, 1892 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - David Copperfield (Box 4, Folder 9)
- [House Dramatics]
  - Jun. 16, 1892 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Colombe's Birthday (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Olla Podrida
  - Jan. 18, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Box and Cox (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Apples (Box 4, Folder 11)
- [House Dramatics]
  - Feb. 4, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - The Obstinate Family (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Tertium Quid
  - Feb. 15, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - The Rivals (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Wallace House
  - Mar. 1, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Much Ado About Nothing (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Lawrence House
  - May 3, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Marie Stuart (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Scenes from Schiller's (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Dewey House
  - May 11, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - The Unexpected Guests (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Sarm Ganok
  - May 17, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Prince Karl (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Morris House
  - May 24, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Our Mutual Friend (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Tertium Quid
  - Nov. 15, 1893 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - A Scrap of Paper (Box 5, Folder 1)
- [Hubbard House]
  - [1893] (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Huckleberry Finn (Box 5, Folder 2)
- [House Dramatics]
  - 1893 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Pepperpot's Little Pets (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Morris House
  - [1893] (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Elsie Dinsmore (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Hubbard House
  - Jan. 24, 1894 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Proverbs in Porcelain (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Olla Podrida
  - Feb. 28, 1894 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - The Russian Honeymoon (Box 5, Folder 6)
- [Mrs. Snowe's House]
  - Mar. 10, 1894 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Tulu (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Morris House
  - May 29, 1894 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Overheard in Arcady (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Dickinson House
  - Oct. 13, 1894 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - A Veneered Savage (Box 5, Folder 9)
- to Lawrence House by Class of 1895
  - [1894] (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Children's Party (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Wallace House
  - Nov. 14, 1894 (Box 5, Folder 11.1-11.2)
    - She Stoops to Conquer (Box 5, Folder 11.1-11.2)
- Sarm Ganok
  - May 2, 1894 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Masque of Culture (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Dewey House
  - Oct. 17, [1895] (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - The Mousetrap (Box 5, Folder 13)
- [Morris House]
  - Oct. 12, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - The Cool Collegians (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Dewey House
  - Nov. 16, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - The Rose and the Ring (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Tertium Quid
  - Nov. 20, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - The Love Chase (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Voice Club
  - Jan. 16, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Achilles in Scyros (Box 5, Folder 17)
      (see Vox Club Dramatics, 52.Speech.VC)
- [House Dramatics]
  - Apr. 22, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Cranford (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Lawrence House
  - Feb. 19, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Esmerelda (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Morris House
  - May 8, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - A Man of Letters (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Dickinson House
  - Jan. 15, 1896 (Box 6, Folder 1.1)
    - The Amazons (Box 6, Folder 1.1)
  - Jan. 15, 1896 (Box 6, Folder 1.2)
    - The Amazons - photo album (Box 6, Folder 1.2)
- [Elm Street]
  - Feb. 21, 1896 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - The Jack Trust (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Sarm Ganok
  - Apr. 22, 1896 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - The Critic (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Wallace House
  - Nov. 18, 1896 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Fair Barbarian (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Phi Kappa Psi
  - Nov. 7, 1896 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Donna Diana (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Wallace House
  - [1897] (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - A Man from Blakely's (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Elocution Department
  - [1897 or 1898] (Box 6, Folder 7)
    (see English Department - Dramatics 59.2 / Eng. Cl)
- Lawrence House
  - Feb. 24, 1897 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Money (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Latin Club
  - Mar. 31, 1897 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Adelphoe of Terence (Box 6, Folder 9)
      (see Department Clubs - Latin Club Dramatics 59.2 Clubs / La Dr. / 1897)
- Tertium Quid
  - Dec. 15, 1897 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - The Hunchback (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Morris House
  - May 5, 1897 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Heir at Law (Box 6, Folder 11)
- [Alpha - Phi Kappa Psi]
  - May 26, 1897 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Nance Oldfield (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Olla Podrida
  - Mar. 2, 1898 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - A Scrap of Paper (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Dickinson House
  - Mar. 23, 1898 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Wheel Of Love (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Miss Tucker's, 84 Elm
  - 1897-1898 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Alice in Wonderland (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Wallace House
  - Nov. 16, 1898 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - A Russian Honeymoon (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Sarm Ganok
  - Jun. 1, 1898 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Fanchon the Cricket (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Phi Kappa Psi
  - Jun. 11, 1898 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Rouge et Vert, or Five Long Years (Box 7, Folder 6)
- [House Dramatics]
  - [1898] (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Cool Collegians (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Wallace House
  - Dec. 1898 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - A Russian Honeymoon (Box 7, Folder 8)
- The Belmont
  - Mar. 4, 1898 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Ingomar (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Lawrence House
  - Feb. 18, 1899 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - The Belle's Stratagem (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Morris House
  - Mar. 22, 1899 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Esmerelda (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Tyler House
  - Nov. 19, 1899 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - The Best Laid Plans (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Olla Podrida
  - Nov. 22, 1899 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - For Half a Million (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - A Husband No More (Box 7, Folder 13)
- 9 Belmont
  - Dec. 2, 1899 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - A Perplexing Situation (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Dickinson House
  - Dec. 6, 1899 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Lovers of Romance (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Hubbard House
  - [1899-1900] (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - The Cranford Play (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Informal skits [1899-1900] (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Tertium Quid
  - Oct. 31, 1899 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Marriage Ceremony (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Apr. 25, 1900 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Ralph Roister Doister (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Wallace House
  - [1900] (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - (unidentified) (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Plymouth Hall
  - Feb. 24, 1900 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - An Engaging Position (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Tyler House
  - Feb. 24, 1900 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - The Christmas Boxes (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Sarm Ganok
  - Mar. 14, 1900 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - The Critic (Box 7, Folder 23)
- (unidentified) - photograph [1899] (Box 7, Folder 24)
- [House Dramatics]
  - [1900-1901] (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Fourth of July, or Any Old Thing (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Lawrence House
  - Oct. 2, 1900 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Julius Caesar (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Tenney House (classes '00, '01, '02)
  - Nov. 10, 1900 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - A Pair of Lunatics (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Tyler House
  - Dec. 5, 1900 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - To Serve for House and Fee (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - [1901] (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - The Golfiacs (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Phi Kappa Psi
  - Feb. 16, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Adventure of Lady Ursula (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Morris House
  - Feb. 20, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Bataille des Dames (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Lawrence House
  - Mar. 20, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - White Aprons (Box 7, Folder 32)
- French Club
  - Apr. 24, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Les Deux Sourds (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Les Precieuses (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Ridicules (Box 7, Folder 33)
      (see Department Clubs - French Club - Dramatics - 59.2 Clubs / E-F)
- Wallace House
  - May 1, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Engaged (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Dewey, Hatfield, Haven - Wesley Houses
  - Dec.4, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Cricket on the Hearth (Box 7, Folder 35)
- Albright House
  - Dec. 11, 1901 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Fanchon the Cricket (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Olla Podrida
  - Feb. 8, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Perils of the Sea (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Tertium Quid
  - Feb. 12, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Lady of Lyons (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Albright House
  - Mar. 5, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - The Benefactress (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Dickinson House
  - Mar. 19, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - The Sevres Cup (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Phi Kappa Psi
  - May 10, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - The Amazons (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Morris House
  - Nov.4, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Little Lord Fauntleroy (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Washburn-Tenney Houses
  - Nov. 19, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - The Lord of Braunfels (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Wallace House
  - Dec. 10, 1902 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - The Rivals (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Lawrence House
  - Feb. 11, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - The Rose and the Ring (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Tyler House
  - Apr. 29, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Trelawny of Wells (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Phi Kappa Psi
  - May 6, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - She Stoops to Conquer (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Albright House
  - Oct. 10, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Who's Who (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Hatfield House
  - Oct. 21, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - The Fatal Message (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Lawrence House
  - Nov. 17, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - The Baron's Victim (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Haven House
  - Dec. 2, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - A Cup of Tea (Box 8, Folder 15)
- S.C. Council
  - Dec. 9, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Monsieur Bouquet (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - From the West (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Dewey-Hatfield Houses
  - Dec. 16, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - The Land of the Heart's Desire (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Morris House
  - [1904] (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Mr. Bob (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Albright House
  - Mar. 2, 1904 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - A Rose of Plymouth Town (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Haven House
  - Mar. 23, 1904 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Alice In Wonderland (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Alpha-Phi Kappa Psi
  - May 25, 1904 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Captain Jinks (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Owl's Nest
  - May 21, 1904 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - The Best Laid Plans (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Hubbard House
  - Nov. 20, 1904 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - King Rene's Daughter (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Dickinson House
  - Dec. 17, 1904 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Our Mutual Friend (Box 8, Folder 24)
- 9 Belmont
  - Mar. 25, 1905 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - The Best Laid Plans (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Chapin House
  - Mar. 8, 1905 (Box 8, Folder 26)